Abhishek Hegde

Software Engineer

' Abhishek has a very articulative nature. He often looks for different ways to solve a problem and his enthusiasm for Machine Learning is amazing. If he doesn't get something he keeps on trying, looking for other resorts till he himself finds at peace with the subject matter. He has extensive knowledge of Data Science and hunger to strive further hard to

> -Saurav Kumar (Senior Analyst at Accenture)

' I would rank him in first five, among the top students, I have taught in the past five years in respect of his programming ability and research skills.Overall, Abhishek is an avid-learner and highly dedicated towards his academics and his career as a whole. He has good analytical skills and is always excited to work with new technologies. His overall intelligence is also reflected in his grades for the course, which were by far one of the best in the class. I believe Abhishek would definitely be an asset to whichever organization he would work for.

> -Dr. Vani Priya (Associate Professor at Sir MVIT)

' Abhishek is very passionate about Business Analytics, I have had the privilege of working with him on several data science projects. He is very hardworking and knows how to use data to solve business problems. He is someone I would always love to have on my team. '

> -Chaithanya Kumar A (Data Scientist Intern at Stylumia)

Skills

Data Science (Python, EDA, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, SQL, Tableau, Problem Solving.),

Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SharePoint), **Problem Solving** (5 Star Gold Level Coder at HackerRank C++ / Python)

Certifications

Business Analytics Nanodegree, Udacity School of Al

Deep Learning Nanodegree, Udacity School of Al

Data Scientist Track, DataCamp

Machine Learning A-Z, Udemy

Problem Solving, HackerRank

Tableau 10 A-Z, Udemy

About

A highly ambitious IT graduate, skilled in data science and software development, possessing a unique mix of business and technical experience.

Professional Experience

Micro Focus, Software Engineer Aug 2020 - present | Bengaluru

Autoliv India, Web Development Intern (SharePoint) Jan 2020 - Feb 2020 | Bengaluru

• Worked with the Automations team on SharePoint development projects, based primarily on dHTML: JS & jQuery with use of AJAX API calls, to design web parts for the company's intranet website.

Sarso Biznet International Pvt.Ltd, Business Team Lead Dec 2016 - May 2018 | Bengaluru

• Lead a business team of 60+ associates in a direct selling business and generated an overall turnover of 6lac+ INR for the company. Achieved an official rank in the organization (Top 1% in India). Carried out 200+ business presentations, attended 10+ regional and 4 national leadership conferences.

Education

IIIT-B, PG Diploma in Data Science May 2020 - present | Bengaluru

Sir MVIT, BE in Information Sciecne & Engineering 2016 - 2020 | Bengaluru | 8.53 CGPA

Projects

Dog Breed Classification using CNNs and Transfer Learning in Pytorch, Deep Learning Nanodegree Given an Image of a dog the algorithm will identify an estimate of the canine's breed. If supplied an image of a human, the code will identify the resembling dog breed

Autonomous Driving Simulator, BE Capstone Project Built a self-driving AI using CNN and image processing using OpenCV, tested on the open source Udacity Nanoprogramme Simulator to autonomously detect the appropriate steering angle, torque and braking based on dashboard cam input images.

Tableau Project: YouTube US View Trends,

Business Analytics Nanodegree

Built a dashboard containing view trends on YouTube from 2006-2018, visualized by category, titles, geography and channel, altogether filterable by a common Year Filter. Created from a dataset of over 22K videos.

Generation of faces using GANs,

Deep Learning Nanodegree

This project is all about defining and training a DCGAN on a dataset of faces. The goal of the project is to get a generator network to generate new images of faces that look as realistic as possible.